<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Paula Rettl</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hud6529b43832e4c596d0e68f65935fca1_5339_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Words can hurt: how political communication can change the pace of an epidemic</title>
      <link>/project/covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/covid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[with &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/view/lucas-argentieri-mariani&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lucas Mariani&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/view/gagete-miranda/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jessica Gagete-Miranda&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compliance with mandated health measures has substantial effects on public health, particularly during epidemics. We analyze how political leaders influence such compliance by exploiting President Bolsonaro’s display of skepticism towards COVID-19 during pro-government demonstrations in Brazil. We compare trends of the disease spread around the demonstrations’ date in municipalities with different levels of support for the President. After the demonstrations, the disease spread faster in pro-Bolsonaro municipalities. The results are driven not only by people’s agglomerating during the demonstrations but also by lower compliance with social distancing. Finally, we rule out that pre-existing differences in health-related behavior explain the results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Export Shocks, Insurance Schemes and Political Behavior in Brazil</title>
      <link>/project/commodities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/commodities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Economic shocks have important implications for political behavior. Yet, similar shocks lead to different political outcomes. The question is why. Combining insights from political behavior and public economics, I argue that reliance on either public or private insurance schemes helps explain heterogeneous political consequences of economic shocks. Ex- amining three Presidential elections in Brazil, I find that the electoral response to export shocks in the 2010s varies at the regional level. By analyzing survey data, I show this is mainly due to Evangelicals and conditional cash transfers beneficiaries responding differently to the shock. These findings suggest that whether individuals and com- munities rely on welfare state benefits or church services to overcome economic hardship helps explain heterogeneity in the political conse- quences of economic shocks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elderly</title>
      <link>/project/elderly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/elderly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Detailed description here&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Threat perceptions and anti-immigration attitudes</title>
      <link>/project/immigration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/immigration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Detailed description here&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
